Herbert A. Philbrick Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- 2001 Addition, 1925-1993 (Box 274-290)
  - Subject File
    - USSR, 1956-1957 (Box 282)
    - Worker, 1952-1957, undated
    - Young Americans for Freedom
      - General, 1963-1975, undated
      - International Communism on Trial, 1968
  - Speeches and Writings
    - Articles, 1953-1966, 1982-1989, undated
    - Book reviews, 1954, undated
    - Debates, undated
    - Forewords and prefaces, 1955, undated
    - Letters to editors, 1959-1966, 1977, undated
    - Miscellaneous writings, 1967, 1987, undated
    - Newsletters
      - Dollar Hollar, 1963-1967, undated, (2 folders)
      - Herb Philbrick's News Bulletin, 1964-1967, 1975-1977, undated
    - Newspaper columns
      - Compilation, 1952-1958, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1953-1957 (Box 283)
      - Drafts, 1952-1958
      - Notes, 1955, undated
    - Notes, 1953-1956, 1988, undated, (2 folders)
    - Speeches
      - Contracts, 1954, 1966-1973
      - Itineraries, 1954-1973, undated, (3 folders)
      - Lecture Bureaus, 1952-1973, 1981-1983, undated, (6 folders)
      - Miscellany, undated
      - Notes, 1963, undated (Box 284)
      - Promotional material, 1953-1972, 1982, undated, (2 folders)
      - Research material, 1950, 1957-1983, undated, (2 folders)
      - Speaking engagements
        - 1949-1964, (6 folders)
        - 1965-1976, (11 folders) (Box 285)
        - 1977-1991, undated, (5 folders) (Box 286)
      - Texts
        - 1955-1982, (6 folders)
        - 1983-1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 287)
  - Miscellany
    - Biographical material
      - Miscellany, 1952-1969, 1979-1981, 1988, undated
      - Press clippings, 1949-1991, undated
    - Childhood material, 1925-1933, undated
    - Church activities, 1982-1987, undated
    - Employment, 1977, undated
    - Film, television, and radio activities
      - “Let Freedom Ring,” radio program, 1961, undated
      - Miscellaneous appearances, 1954, 1962-1967, undated
      - National Education Program films, 1963, undated
      - “World War III”
        - Casca records, 1958-1959, undated, (2 folders)
        - Correspondence, 1958-1959, undated, (7 folders) (Box 288)
        - Miscellany, 1955-1959, undated
        - Production material, 1959, undated
        - Resource material
          - Miscellaneous, 1951, 1957-1969, undated, (2 folders) (Box 289)
          - Program subjects, 1948, 1955-1960, undated, (10 folders); (7 folders) (Box 290)
    - Financial records, 1937-1939, 1964-1965, 1986
    - Honors and awards, 1955-1962, 1973, 1980, undated
    - Office files
      - Coded names, 1951-1952, 1968-1974, 1987
      - Memoranda to secretaries, 1960, 1966, undated
- 2023 Addition, 1947-1992 (Box 291-295)
  Correspondence, scripts, notes, promotional material, newspaper clippings, and printed matter.
  - General correspondence (Box 291)
    - 1947-1950 (Box 291)
    - 1952, (3 folders) (Box 291)
    - 1953-1959 (Box 291)
    - 1960-1963 (Box 291)
    - 1964, (2 folders) (Box 291)
    - 1965-1969 (Box 292)
    - 1970 (Box 292)
    - 1971 (Box 292)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 292)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 292)
    - 1976-1978 (Box 292)
    - 1980-1992, undated (Box 292)
  - I Lived 3 Lives, 1968, 1976, undated (Box 292)
  - Let Freedom Ring (Box 293)
    - Broadcasts (Box 293)
      - No. 1, 1961, Jan. 6 (Box 293)
      - No. 2, 1961, Jan. 11 (Box 293)
      - No. 4, 1961, Jan. 14 (Box 293)
      - No. 5, 1961, Jan. 18 (Box 293)
      - No. 7, 1961, Jan. 23 (Box 293)
      - No. 8, 1961, Jan. 25 (Box 293)
      - No. 9, 1961, Jan. 27 (Box 293)
      - No. 11, 1961, Feb. 1 (Box 293)
      - No. 13, 1961, Feb. 6 (Box 293)
      - No. 14, 1961, Feb. 8 (Box 293)
      - No. 15, 1961, Feb. 10 (Box 293)
      - No. 16, 1961, Feb. 13 (Box 293)
      - No. 33, 1961, Mar. 24 (Box 293)
      - No. 34, 1961, Mar. 27 (Box 293)
      - No. 41, 1961, Apr. 17 (Box 293)
      - No. 42, 1961, Apr. 19 (Box 293)
      - No. 47, 1961, May 3 (Box 293)
      - No. 48, 1961, May 5 (Box 293)
      - Unnumbered, 1961, May 11 (Box 293)
      - Unnumbered, 1961, May 12 (Box 293)
      - No. 55, 1961, May 15 (Box 293)
      - No. 56, 1961, May 17 (Box 293)
      - No. 57, 1961, May 19 (Box 293)
      - No. 59, 1961, May 24 (Box 293)
      - No. 60, 1961, May 26 (Box 293)
      - No. 62, 1961, May 31 (Box 293)
      - No. 64, 1961, June 5 (Box 293)
      - No. 74, 1961, June 30 (Box 293)
      - No. 77, 1961, July 7 (Box 293)
      - No. 78, 1961, July 10 (Box 293)
      - No. 79, 1961, July 12 (Box 293)
      - No. 80, 1961, July 14 (Box 293)
      - Unnumbered, 1961, Aug. 11 (Box 293)
      - Unnumbered, 1961, Sept. 20 (Box 293)
      - Unnumbered, 1961, Sept. 22 (Box 293)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 293)
    - Research materials, 1960 (Box 294)
    - Spot announcements, 1961 (Box 294)
  - Speeches and writings, 1955-1981 (Box 294)
    - Associated clubs, 1968-1974, (2 folders) (Box 294)
    - Itineraries, 1967-1968, undated (Box 294)
    - Lecture bureaus, 1966-1970, undated, (2 folders) (Box 294)
    - Lecture requests, 1965-1973, (2 folders) (Box 294)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965, undated (Box 294)
    - Notes, 1974-1981 (Box 295)
    - Promotional material, 1955-1970, undated (Box 295)
    - Speaking engagements, 1952-1977, (2 folders) (Box 295)
    - Writing drafts, undated (Box 295)
  - Miscellany, 1967-1981 (Box 295)
    - Biographical material, 1971-1975, undated (Box 295)
    - Church activities, 1981 (Box 295)
    - Mailing lists, 1967-1972, undated (Box 295)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 295)
- Oversize, 1949 (Box OV 1)
  Scrapbook of newspaper clippings.
  Arranged and described according to the series, container, and folder from which the item was removed.
  - Addition (Box OV 1)
    - Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA)
      - Testimony, 1949 (Container 277)
- Top Secret, 1946 (Box TS 1)
  One memorandum.
  - Subject File (Box TS 1)
    - State Department, 1946 (Container 183)